freesamples.org 2013-05-21

# Free Samples: » Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

FreeSamples.org is committed to respecting the privacy rights of users of the Website (all capitalized terms not defined in this notice have the same meanings as in FreeSamples.org’ Website Terms of Use, which is incorporated herein by reference). FreeSamples.org created this Privacy Policy to give You confidence as You visit and use the Website, and to demonstrate its commitment to fair information practices and to the protection of privacy.

This Privacy Policy is only applicable to the Website and not to any Third-Party Websites, which may have data collection, storage and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy. For additional information, see the section concerning Third-Party Websites, below.

BY USING THE WEBSITE, YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTOOD, AND AGREE TO THE TERMS OF, THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND OR DO NOT AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU MUST IMMEDIATELY LEAVE THE WEBSITE.

Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, each time You use the Website You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the end) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website. For additional information, see the section concerning Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy, below.

**1.INFORMATION COLLECTION PRACTICES**

**(a)Traffic Data.** Like most website operators, FreeSamples.org automatically gathers information of the sort that browsers automatically make available, including: (i) IP addresses; (ii) domain servers; (iii) types of computers accessing the Website; and (iv) types of Web browsers accessing the Website (collectively “Traffic Data”). Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify You.

**(b)Cookies.** A “Cookie” is a string of information that a website stores on a user’s computer, and that the user’s browser provides to the website each time the user submits a query to the website. The purpose of a Cookie is to identify the user as a unique user of the Website. FreeSamples.org uses Cookies to customize Your experience on the Website to Your interests, to ensure that You do not see the same advertisements or informational messages repeatedly, and to store Your password so You do not have to re-enter it each time You visit the Website. For additional information on FreeSamples.org’s uses of Cookies, see the section concerning Information Use and Disclosure Practices/Traffic Data and Information Gathered Using Cookies, below.

IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO HAVE COOKIES PLACED ON YOUR COMPUTER, YOU SHOULD SET YOUR BROWSERS TO REFUSE COOKIES BEFORE ACCESSING THE WEBSITE, WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT CERTAIN OF THE SERVICES AND CERTAIN FEATURES OF THE WEBSITE MAY NOT FUNCTION PROPERLY WITHOUT THE AID OF COOKIES. IF YOU REFUSE COOKIES, YOU ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY RESULTING LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY.

**(c) Personal Information.** In order for You to use certain of the Services, You may be asked to provide FreeSamples.org certain information that personally identifies You (“Personal Information”). Personal Information includes, without limitation: (1) “Contact Data” (such as Your name and e-mail address) and (2) “Demographic Data” (such as age and time zone). In each case, You will be asked to provide Personal Information; the Website will not gather it surreptitiously. FreeSamples.org may supplement the Personal Information You provide with additional Personal Information gathered from public sources or from third-parties (e.g., consumer reporting agencies) who may lawfully provide such information to FreeSamples.org.

You are under no obligation to provide Personal Information, with the caveat that Your refusal to do so may prevent You from using certain of the Services.

**(d) Information You Make Public.** The Website contains features (e.g. forums) that permit You to upload, post, transmit, display, perform or distribute content, information or other, including Your Personal Information. Any information that You choose to disclose by means of such features becomes public information over which FreeSamples.org is unable to exercise control. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose Your Personal Information by means of such features, and You agree to assume all responsibility for doing so.

**2.INFORMATION USE AND DISCLOSURE PRACTICES**

**(a)Traffic Data and Information Gathered Using Cookies**

FreeSamples.org analyzes Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies to help FreeSamples.org better understand who is using the Website and how they are using it. By identifying patterns and trends in usage, FreeSamples.org is able to better design the Website to improve Your experience, and to serve You more relevant and interesting content and advertisements. From time to time, FreeSamples.org may release Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website. FreeSamples.org does not attempt to link information gathered using Cookies to Personal Information.

**(b)Personal Information**

**(i)Generally**. FreeSamples.org uses Your Contact Data to send You information about FreeSamples.org and FreeSamples.org’s products and services, and to contact You when necessary in connection with the Services. FreeSamples.org uses Your Demographic Data to customize and tailor Your experience on the Website. As with Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies, from time to time FreeSamples.org may release Demographic Data in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website.

**(ii)Disclosure Practices**

Except under the following circumstances, FreeSamples.org will keep Your Personal Information private, and will not sell or otherwise share it with third parties:

&bull Disclosure in Connection with Services. FreeSamples.org discloses Personal Information to those who help it provide Services, including those who perform technical, administrative and data processing tasks such as hosting, billing, fulfillment, and data storage and security.

&bull License to User Content. As stated in the Website Terms of Use, by using the Website, You grant the FreeSamples.org Parties the right to publish Your name and any username of Yours in connection with the FreeSamples.org Parties’ exercise of their license in and to Your User Content. You further waive any claims arising from the FreeSamples.org Parties’ exercise of that right. For additional information, see Terms of Use Section 11, regarding User Content.

&bull By Law or to Protect Rights. FreeSamples.org discloses Personal Information when required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order, or when FreeSamples.org believes in its sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of FreeSamples.org, third parties or the public at large.

&bull Business Transfers; Bankruptcy. FreeSamples.org reserves the right to transfer all Personal Information in its possession to a successor organization in the event of a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of FreeSamples.org’ assets. Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, the use and disclosure of all transferred Personal Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy, or to a new privacy policy if You are given notice of that new privacy policy and an opportunity to affirmatively opt-out of it. Personal Information submitted or collected after a transfer, however, may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by FreeSamples.org’ successor organization.

**3.SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

FreeSamples.org has implemented and maintains reasonable security procedures and practices to protect against the unauthorized access, use, modification, destruction or disclosure of Your Personal Information.

**4.NEWSLETTERS**

You may subscribe to receive the FreeSamples.org newsletter at FreeSamples.org. Each newsletter has clear instructions about how to unsubscribe. Should You subscribe to the newsletter and later wish to unsubscribe, You can opt-out of receiving the newsletter at anytime by following the unsubscribe instructions contained therein.

**5.LOST OR STOLEN INFORMATION**

You must promptly notify us if Your user name or password is lost, stolen or used without permission. In such and event, we will remove that user name or password from Your account and update our records accordingly.

**6.USER ABILITY TO ACCESS, UPDATE, AND CORRECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**

FreeSamples.org wants Your Personal Information to be complete and accurate. As stated in the Website Terms of Use, by using the Website, You represent and warrant that all information You provide on any registration form or otherwise in connection with Your use of the Website and Services will be complete and accurate, and that You will update that information as necessary to maintain its completeness and accuracy. To confirm the completeness and accuracy of, or make changes to, Your Personal Information, visit Your personal profile. Through Your personal profile You may review and update You Personal Information that we have already collected.

**7.THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES**

FreeSamples.org neither owns nor controls Third-Party Websites. Accordingly, Third-Party Websites are under no obligation to comply with this Privacy Policy except with respect to Personal Information provided directly to them by FreeSamples.org. Before visiting or providing Personal Information to a Third-Party Website, You should inform Yourself of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of that Third-Party Website, and should take those steps necessary to, in Your discretion, protect Your privacy.

**8.PROMOTIONAL ACTIVITIES**

From time to time, FreeSamples.org may conduct contests, giveaways and other promotions (collectively, “Promotional Activities”). Any information submitted in connection with Promotional Activities will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. From time to time, FreeSamples.org may also ask You to participate in surveys designed to help FreeSamples.org improve the Websites or Services. Any Personal Information provided to FreeSamples.org in connection with any survey will be used only in relation to that survey, and will be disclosed to third parties not bound by this Privacy Policy only in aggregated form.

**9.UPDATES AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, FreeSamples.org reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, update, change or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such update, change or modification on this page. Any such addition, update, change or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Website. Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, each time You use the Website You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the end) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website. Unless FreeSamples.org obtains Your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policy.

Effective Date: [30/11/2008]
